Camila Ribeiro Fernandes

Apt 79, The Lighthouse / George's Street Lower - Dun Laoghaire
Phone: 087 3691589 / Email: camilarf@gmail.com
LinkedIn Link | Portfolio Link | GitHub Link

PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a full stack junior developer looking for a position that makes best use of my existing abilities and allows me to learn, develop new skills and master a career in software development. With 15+ years of experience in the customer facing industry, I'm a good listener with strong communication skills, very articulate and always looking to improve. I have strong Business Management experience having worked as Salon Manager which required a high level of attention to detail. Being able to juggle unexpected situations helps me to prioritize tasks and work in an agile way.

SKILLS

- Applications Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook), Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, Sketch, InVision
- **Programming Languages** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python(Flask, Django)
- Database Systems MySQL, Mongo DB
- Well Organized with Solid Administration Skills
- Remote learning reinforced my ability to communicate remotely through platforms such as Slack Channel
- Self-starter and internally motivated
- Technically capable to write and analyse code including maintainability, reuse, clean code
- Strong communication skills ability to communicate effectively with a wide range of individuals and groups e.g. clients, colleagues, suppliers and senior management. Strong presentation skills and confidence demonstrated by experience of delivering presentations to small groups
- Teamwork ability to work with several representatives from different disciplines concurrently to ensure successful completion of tasks. Managed the induction and supervision of new staff members
- Time management & agile way studying online gave me the ability to work on my own
 initiative towards tight deadlines whilst maintaining attention to detail. Establishment of
 timelines for completion of tasks in stages

EDUCATION

2019 – 2020 <u>Full Stack Software Development Diploma</u> / Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

Qualifications: Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Modules: Programme Preliminaries, Programming Paradigms, HTML Fundamentals, CSS Fundamentals, User Centric Frontend Development, JavaScript Fundamentals, Interactive Frontend Development, Python Fundamentals, Practical Python, Data Centric Development, Full Stack Frameworks with Django

2019 – 2020 Professional Diploma UX Design / UX Design Institute - Dublin, Ireland

Qualifications: Diploma UX Designer

Modules: Introduction to UX design, User research, User goals, Structure and Navigation, Interactions, Design principles, Design patterns, Mobile, Workflows, Prototyping and Wireframing

2015 Colour Specialist / L'Oreal - Dublin, Ireland

2004 – 2008 <u>Bsc (hons) degree Fashion Business</u> / International University Anhembi Morumbi - Sao Paulo, Brazil

Students formed in the course will be ready to work directly or indirectly in operational or managerial activities of the commercial areas of the fashion market companies. The sectors of marketing and development department stores and e-commerce fashion companies are major employers of graduates. The industries of Textile Chain have a broad absorption in the areas of marketing and development of new product lines.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

October 2019 - Present Career break dedicated to IT professional development

2018 – 2019 Salon Manager & Colour Specialist / Bernie Coiffeur - Dublin, Ireland

- Keeping financial records, paid vendors and ensured all invoices were paid on time
- Reviewed performance data (financial, sales, and activity levels), responsible for monitoring goal progress and team productivity and all ongoing operational activities
- Kept a strong client base and ensured customer satisfaction
- Provided a full range of the services offered by the salon, including colouring techniques and advanced cutting & styling

2012 - 2018 Salon Manager & Colour Specialist / Trim Hair Salon - Dublin, Ireland

- An experienced team leader promoted to Manager position, delegating tasks to staff throughout the day in order to keep business, sales and services flowing accordingly with targets
- Responsible for opening and closing the premises
- Maintained an appointment calendar through scheduling working 5 years with Phorest Software
- Analytical thinker helped staff to achieve results ensuring clients satisfaction
- Managed social media channels such as Facebook, Instagram and Twitter
- Developed marketing strategies to boost sales to achieve Salon targets
- Ensured salon stock and office stock was at sufficient levels at all times
- Implemented junior education teaching theory and practical classes
- Advised clients on their hair care needs and homecare prescription selling the right products to meet client needs
- Always followed Health and Safety standards carrying Allergy Alert Test on all clients and advising coworkers to do the same
- Detailed product knowledge, chemical composition of the substances used to ensure the
 appropriate mixing ratio and awareness of the chemical processes that the substances may
 undergo, such as understanding chemical reactions and correct disposal methods

HOBBIES

• Spending time with my dogs, going for walks and workout are things that help me to relax and smile!